Finding Aid for the Lawrence Morton Papers LSC.1522
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Research Material
  - Stravinsky, Books Relating to or Referring to
    - Amberg, George--Ballet in America., 1954, fourth printing. (Box 60)
      New York: Mentor Books published by the New American Library of World Literature, Incorporated.
    - Taper, Bernard--Balanchine., 1963. (Box 61)
      New York, Evanston and London: Harper and Row, Publishers, Incorporated.
    - Rorem, Ned--Setting the tone: Essays and a diary., 1984. (Box 61)
      New York: Limelight Editions.
    - --I.F. Stravinsky., 1973. (Box 61)
      Moscow.
    - Sachs, Curt--World history of the dance., 1952. (Box 61)
      Translated by Bessie Schonberg.
      New York: Seven Arts-Publishers.
    - Pushkin, Alexander--The poems, prose and plays of Alexander Pushkin., 1936. (Box 61)
      Selected and edited, with an introduction by Avrahm Yarmolinsky.
      The Modern Library. New York: Random House, Incorporated.
    - Chujoy, Anatole--The New York City Ballet., 1953. (Box 61)
    - Rubinstein, Arthur--My Young Years., 1973. (Box 62)
    - Rubinstein, Arthur--My many years., 1980. (Box 62)
      Insert after printing information--Review by Robert Kirsch (Los Angeles Times 25 February ?).
    - Rimsky-Korsakov, Nikolay--My musical life., 1925. (Box 62)
      Translated from the revised second Russian edition by Judah A. Joffe. Edited with an introduction by Carl van Vechten. Second edition, revised.
    - Sert, Misia--Two or three muses: The memoirs of Misia Sert., 1953. (Box 62)
      Translated from the French by Moura Budberg. Foreword by Tamara Karsarvina.
      London: Museum Press Limited.
    - Maslenikov, Oleg A--The frenzied poets: Andrey Biely and the Russian symbolists., 1952. (Box 62)
      Insert after free end paper review of Steven Cassedy, Selected Essays of Andrey Bely. Berkeley: University of California Press. by R.D. Reeve (New York Times Book Review 9 February 1986).
    - [Pushkin] Puskin, Aleksander--Poemi e liriche., 1960. (Box 62)
      Versioni, introduzione e note di Tommaso Landolfi.
      Torino: Giulio Einaudi, editore.
    - Mitchell, Donald, and Hans Keller, (eds.)--Benjamin Britten: A commentary on his works from a group of specialists., 1952. (Box 63)
      New York: Philosophical Library, Incorporated.
    - Nettl, Paul--The story of dance music., 1947. (Box 63)
      New York: The Philosophical Library, Incorporated.
    - Corona Mundi--Roerich., 1924. (Box 63)
      New York: International Art Center.
    - Korn, Richard--Orchestral accents., 1956. (Box 63)
      New York: Farrar, Straus and Cudahy, Incorporated.
      Includes a chapter on Stravinsky.
    - Steegmuller, Francis--Cocteau: A biography., 1970. (Box 63)
      Boston & Toronto: Little, Brown & Company, Limited.
      Insert after free end paper, reviews by Robert Mazzocco (New York Review of Books 28 January 1971) and unsigned (New Yorker n.d.).
    - Pasler, Jann--Professional dossier including reproductions of significant publications., [1984]. (Box 70)
    - Buckle, Richard--In Search of Diaghilev., 1956. (Box 91)
      New York: Thomas Nelson & Sons.
      Some pencil notes in L.M.'s hand.
    - Kochno, Boris avec la collaboration de Maria Luz--Le Ballet., 1954. (Box 91)
      Lithographie originale de Picasso.
      France: Librairie Hachette.
    - Kochno, Boris--Diaghilev and the ballet russes., 1970. (Box 92)
      Translated from the French by Adrienne Foulke. Designed by Bea Feitler.
      New York & Evanston: Harper & Row, Publishers, Incorporated.
      Insert Anna Kisselgoff, He was the 'idea man' for Diaghilev and Balanchine (New York Times 28 July 1985). Inscribed: Thought you might like to see this. How did the symphony of a thousand go. CW.
    - Pincherle, Marc--Histoire illustree de la musique., 1959. (Box 92)
      Switzerland: Librairie Gallimard.
      In L.M.'s hand on front paste-down end paper: Stravinsky p.195 photo p.202.
    - Levinson, Andre--La Danse: S'aujourd' hui / etudes--notes portraits., 1929. (Box 93)
      Paris: Editions Duchartre et Van Buggenhoudt.
    - Kirstein, Lincoln--The New York City Ballet., 1973. (Box 94)
      Photographs by Martha Swope and George Platt Lynes.
      Insert Lincoln Kirstein Ballet for everyone?, The New York Review of Books, 23 November 1978 25(18) & Bernard Taper An eternal present The New Yorker 22 October 1973.
    - Pro Arte Quartet--Les concerts Pro Arte Xe anniversaire: Bruxelles 1921-1931., 1930.; Photocopy. (Box 98)
      Bruxelles: Palais des Beaux-Arts de Bruxelles.
    - Bochet, Henri--Le Conservatoire de Musique de Geneve: Son histoire de 1835 a 1935. (Box 127)
      Geneve: Foundation Bartholoni.
    - Baltzai, Dainu--Melodien litauisher Volkslieder, gesammelt und mit ubersetzung, anmerkungenund einleitung im Austrage der Litauischen litterarischen Gesellschaft., 1886. (Box 127)
      Herausgegeben von Christian Bartsch. Erster Teil.
      Heidelberg: Carl Winters Universitats Buchhandlung.
    - Baltzai, Dainu--Melodien Litauischer Volkslieder, gesammelt un mut ubersetzung, anmerkungenund einleitung im Austrage der Litauischen litterarischen Gesellschaft., 1889. (Box 127)
      Herausgegeben bon Christian Bartsch. Zweiter teil.
      Heidelberg: Carl Winters Universitats buchhandlung.
    - Polyakova, Lyudmila--Soviet music., n.d. (Box 127)
      Moscow: Foreign Languages Publishing House.
      This book may relate to Stravinsky, but his name is not mentioned.
  - Stravinsky, Catalogs Related to
    - The New York City Ballet--Stravinsky and Balanchine: Fifty years of partnership 1920-1971., 1971 [ca.].; Inside the gold box. (Box 25)
    - Sotheby's (11 November)--Highly important music manuscripts, printed music, and continental autograph letters and historical documents., 1982. (Box 26)
      London: Sotheby.
      Inserted are articles from the New York Times and the Washington Post of 11 November 1982 reporting the record sale ($548,000) of the sketch score of Le Sacre du Printemps to the Sacher Foundation.
    - Igor Stravinsky: La Carriera Europa., 1982. (Box 28)
    - Stravinsky--Diaghilev (May/June)--An exhibition of works relating to I. Stravinsky, S.D. Diaghilev and their collaborators for the benefit of the Stravinsky--Diaghilev museum in Venice., 1973. (Box 28)
      New York: Cordier & Ekstrom Gallery.
    - Igor Stravinsky: La Carrier Europeene (14 October-30 November)., 1980. (Box 28)
      Musee D'Art Moderne de la Ville de Paris.
    - --Nicolas Roerich., 1974. (Box 30)
      New York: The Nicolas Roerich Museum.
    - Festival D'Automn Paris--Stravinsky., 1980. (Box 30)
    - --Nicolas Roerich., 1974. (Box 30)
    - Kunstmuseum Basel in zusammenarbeit mit der Paul Sacher Stiftung Basel--Strawinsky: Seinnachlass. Sein bild., 1984. (Box 30)
      Inserted are reviews by Robert Craft from the New York Review of Books, John Russell from the New York Times and an unsigned review from Connoiseur June 1984.
    - First London exhibition of paintings by Vera Stravinsky, 7 March-8 April., 1978. (Box 35)
      With an introduction by Stephen Spender, biographical notes by Robert Craft and tributes by Aldous Huxley & Christopher Isherwood.
      London: Crane Kalman Gallery.
    - Mostra Commemorativa dell'opera di Leon Bakst--Bakst exhibition., 1967. (Box 35)
      n.p.: Leon Bakst Galleria del Levante.
    - Ballet and theatre material which will be sold by Sotheby Parke Bernet & Company, (13 March), 1980.; Photocopy. (Box 37)
      Inserted is a photocopy of Larionev Caricature of Diaghilev's circle as a pack of performing dogs.
    - Stravinsky and the dance: A survey of ballet productions: 1910-1962., 1963. (Box 37)
      New York: The Dance Collection of the New York Public Library.
    - Stravinsky and the theatre: A catalogue of decor and costume designs for stage productions of his works, 1910-1962., 1963. (Box 37)
      New York: The New York Public Library.
    - An exhibition of costume and set designs chiefly for Diaghilev's ballets, drawn from the collection of John Carr Doughty, Esq--Diaghilev., 1967. (Box 59)
      Introduction by Richard Buckle.
      London: Arts Council.
    - Ville de Strasbourg--Les ballets Russes de Serge Diaghilev., 1969 15 Mai-15 Septembre. (Box 60)
      Ville de Strasbourg: L'Ancienne Douane.
      On free end paper(verso) in L.M.'s hand: Roerich, 46, 64, facing, 80 facing, 112-113.
    - Pages from the Library of Congress Catalog--Music and Phonorecord--Stravinsky., 1963-1967. (Box 71)
    - Books on music from the collection of the Russian musicologist N.N., n.d. (Box 71)
      New York: Russica Book & Art Shop, Incorporated.
    - Buckle, Richard--The Diaghilev exhibition from the Edinburgh festival., 1954. (Box 91)
      Forbes House, Haldin Street, Hyde Park Corner: The Observer, Limited.
    - Buckle, Richard--The Diaghilev exhibition., 1954. (Box 91)
      College of Art. Lauriston Place: Edinburgh Festival.
    - Baer, Nancy van Norman--Bronislava Nijinska: A dancer's legacy., 1986. (Box 91)
      Preface by Ian McKibbon White.
      The Fine Arts Museum of San Francisco.
    - Serge Lifar collection of ballet set and costume designs., 1965. (Box 92)
      Hartford, Connecticut: Wadsworth Atheneum.
  - Stravinsky, Clippings
    - Bartok, Bela, et al--In memoriam Igor Stravinsky., 1972. (Box 62)
      Budapest: Zenemukiado Vallalat.
      Also by Lajos Bardos, Antal Dorati, Janos Gonda, Kurtag Gyorgy, Paul Henry Lang, Andras Mihaly, Aurel Milloss, Racz-Barblan Yvonne, Laszlo Somfai, Janos Starker, Andras Szollosy and Jeno Zador.
    - Individual works of Stravinsky (57 musical compositions and the Poetics of Music)., 58 clipping files in manila folders. (Box 66)
    - Advertisements, Announcements, etc. (Box 67)
    - Anniversaries, birthdays, celebrations. (Box 67)
    - Ansermet, Ernest. (Box 67)
    - Stravinsky--Auctions. (Box 67)
      Other auction and sales catalogues, those with illustration, are in the desk folder `Stravinsky Portraits'.
    - Balanchine. (Box 67)
    - Biography--sketches, etc.--news. (Box 67)
    - Biographies + studies--reviews. (Box 67)
    - Craft, Robert--Articles by, and about. (Box 67)
    - Craft: Stravinsky, Selected correspondence. (Box 67)
    - Essays (on aspects of S's works). (Box 67)
    - Estate--Manuscripts, etc. (Box 67)
    - Funeral. (Box 67)
    - Interviews (not with R.C.). (Box 67)
    - Honors, awards, etc. (Box 67)
    - Catalogues. (Box 67)
    - Family (father). (Box 67)
    - Various--Campus focus: The composer in academia: Reflections on a theme of Stravinsky., 1970. (Box 68)
      Offprint from College Music Symposium × 1970.
    - Stravinsky--Craft. (Box 68)
      1. Conversations with Igor Stravinsky.
      2. Memories and commentaries.
      3. Expositions and developments.
      4. Themes and episodes.
      5. Dialogues and a diary.
      6. Retrospectives and conclusions.
    - U.S.S.R., 1962. (Box 68)
    - Stravinsky in pictures and documents. (Box 68)
    - Stravinsky [ballet] Festival., June 1972. (Box 68)
    - Reviews of scores--mixed. (Box 68)
    - Record reviews, miscellaneous. (Box 68)
    - Reviews: Concerts. Opera. (Box 68)
    - Reminiscences. (Box 68)
    - White, Eric Walter. (Box 68)
    - Program Notes--Mixed (Translations of vocal texts). (Box 68)
    - Post Mortems, encomiums, etc., obits. (Box 68)
    - Libman: Music at the close. Horgan: Encounter with Stravinsky. Craft: Chronicle of a friendship. Joint and separate reviews--Vera Str and Robert Craft: Pix + Dox. (Box 68)
    - Photographs [of Stravinsky, published]. (Box 68)
    - Nijinsky. (Box 68)
    - Miscellaneous. (Box 68)
    - Polemics. (Box 68)
    - Stravinsky scrapbook., 1960-62. (Box 82)
    - Stravinsky scrapbook., 1928-1962. (Box 82)
      Mostly reviews.
    - At Stravinsky's grave--Holograph translation of article (included) from Novoye Russkoye Slovo (Russian New York Paper)., 1971. (Box 85)
    - Conductors. (Box 86)
      Klemperer, McArthur, Mitropoulos, Ormandy, Rodzinski, Segerstrom, Solomon, Stock, Steinberg, Stokowski, Wallenstein, Dixon, Ansermet--Craft, Mengelberg, Muck, Furtwangler, goldman, Munch, Karajan, Kubelik, Cantelli, Kurtz, Scherman.
    - Rosenthal, Manuel--Composers in Europe. (Box 86)
    - Manuscripts, Autographs. (Box 86)
    - Russian music (Pre USSR). (Box 86)
    - Cocteau. (Box 87)
    - Union of Soviet Socialist Republics., [3 envelopes]. (Box 87)
    - Auden, W.H. (Box 87)
    - Balanchine. (Box 87)
    - Dahl, Ingolf. (Box 87)
    - Koussevitzsky, Serge. Koussevitzky Music Foundation, Berkshire Festival. (Box 88)
    - Rimsky-Korsakoff, Nikolai. (Box 89)
    - Life Magazine: Hemingway, Mozart, Picasso, The corridors of the heart, Balanchine. (Box 98)
  - Stravinsky, Correspondence
    - Various original and photocopied autograph letters and miscellany by Igor and Vera Stravinsky., 1939, 1953-1972, 1982.; 31 items, 42 pieces. (Box 5)
      Includes some musical notes, Stravinsky images and Stravinsky's chart of the cimbalon.
    - Various autographs and mementos of Vera and Igor Stravinsky., 1946-1975.; 49 items, 77 pieces. (Box 5)
    - Souvtchinsky/Stravinsky correspondence. (Box 65)
      Photographic prints and negatives of letters and telegrams including correspondence concerning Souvchinsky's publication of Stravinsky/Ravel and Stravinsky/Debussy letters.
      Ink transcriptions (French) of letters are included, all inside the envelope labeledSouvtchinsky, Pierre.
    - Ansermet, Ernest: Correspondence, 1948 re A's New York performances, Article on Honegger and Gaillards letter, Lausanne program 28 November 1928, with A's article, Letter to Edition Russe de Musique re Symphonies of Wind Instruments., Photographic negatives and proofs. (Box 74)
      Sacre material shot in Geneva.
    - Photographic negatives, one print--[Stravinsky] Correspondence (miscellaneous): Merle Armitage, Carl Winrich, NBC (Davison re Symphony in C broadcast), Chagall, Victor Desarzens, Lukas Foss, Max Ernst, Dr. Maurice Gilbert, Irving Fine, Igor Markevitch, Paul Hindemith, Eugene Goosens. (Box 74)
      The print is of a Gliere letter to Stravinsky, thanking the younger composer for his felicitations on the occasion of Gliere's 75th birthday. Also included is a transcription of the letter.
    - Boulanger, Nadia (Includes Marcel Dupre chorale)., 1949-1961.; Photographic negatives and proofs. (Box 74)
      Twelve letters from Stravinsky to Boulanger.
    - Photographic negatives--Ansermet material--first roll--Geneva., 1 September 1960.; 36 shots, second roll 30 shots. (Box 74)
      Letters to (from?) Stravinsky, Sacre score: revisions, corrections and nouvelle revision.
    - Switzerland., Photographic negatives and proofs. (Box 74)
      Telegram orders by Stravinsky.
    - Diamond, David., 1943-1947.; Photographic negatives and proofs. (Box 74)
      Eleven letters to Stravinsky from Diamond. Four to Diamond from Stravinsky.
    - Markevitch, Igor., n.d.; Photographic negatives and proofs. (Box 74)
      Stravinsky/Markevitch correspondence.
    - Schaeffner, Andre., Photographic negatives and proofs. (Box 74)
      Letters to Stravinsky.
    - Kall, Alexis., 1935-1940.; 14 items, 25 pieces. (Box 85)
      Photocopies of letters to and from Stravinsky from the Kall papers at the Department of Special collections, UCLA.
      See letter from Esther [Leonard] in folder L box 85.
  - Stravinsky, Correspondence About
    - Stravinsky Stamp: Correspondence relating to the production of a Stravinsky stamp. (U.S. 2 cent)., 1980-1982.; 49 items, 70 pieces. (Box 5)
      Detailing L.M.'s successful effort to have the United States Postal issue a stamp in honor of the composer.
    - Taruskin, Richard/Morton., 1983, 1984.; 2 items, 2 pieces. (Box 6)
      re Stravinsky scholarship.
    - Symposium., 1982. (Box 6)
      File of correspondence and manuscripts relating to the International Stravinsky symposium at the University of California at San Diego.
      Includes handout information from the presentations and letters to and from the organizer, Jann Pasler.
    - Stravinsky conducting history at the Los Angeles Philharmonic [incomplete]., n.d [after 1966]. (Box 6)
    - W: Morton/Eric Walter White, Westdeutcher Rundfunk and Norbert Weiss., 1960, 1963, 1985.; 5 items, 7 pieces. (Box 6)
    - T: Morton/Tempo, Los Angeles Times, Travis & Emory., 1960-1982. (Box 6)
      Tempo re Stravinsky article, Times re date of Stravinsky photo, Travis & Emory re acquisitions of literary and musical publications.
    - USSR: Correspondence re trip to the Soviet Union for Stravinsky research., 1959.; 14 items, 22 pieces. (Box 6)
    - USC Stravinsky Institute: Correspondence re unsuccessful attempt to establish a Stravinsky Institute at the University of Southern California., 1978.; 6 items, 9 pieces. (Box 6)
    - UCLA: Morton/Anne Caiger re bequest of the Morton papers to the Department of Special collections--UCLA., 1984.; 2 items, 2 pieces. (Box 6)
    - Stravinsky and Schoenberg in Los Angeles. (Box 69)
      Works of Stravinsky and Schoenberg performed at MEC and Encounters (from L. Stein). Correspondence with E. Fleishman and P. Heyworth about 1981 Festival of Music Made in Los Angeles.
    - Stravinsky letters to music editor, Los Angeles Times., Original & carbon copies of 4 letters. (Box 69)
      Note by L.M. (February 1962) detailing his creation of 2 Stravinsky letters to A. Goldberg, 1 to the Los Angeles Times and the Cure for VD (not L.M.'s title) to Listen.
    - Radlo, Len to Morton. (1), E. Reinbach (2), W. Ricke (2), N. Ricordi (2), F. Routh (3). (Box 69)
    - Recording projects: Morton to Emil Richards, to Nonesuch., 2 items. (Box 69)
    - Roerich: Morton/Nicolas Roerich Museum (3). (Box 69)
      Transcript of Roerich address at the Wanamaker Auditorium, under the auspices of the League of composers, 1930. Cyrillic pamphlet.
    - S: Morton to P. Sacher (1), from E. Schonberger (2), L. Smit (3), M. Stalvey (1), L. Stein (1), H. Stevens (1), G. Stone (1), to T. Stravinsky (1). (Box 69)
      Sacher re gift of I.S.'s ring and cigarette case, Smit (3) re Jeu de cartes), L. Stein (1) re Stravinsky/Schoenberg.
    - Slonimsky, Nicolas/Morton., 1945 (1), 1961 (29), 1965 (1). (Box 69)
      From Slonimsky (1) 1945, (16) 1961, (1) 1965. To Slonimsky (13) 1961 re Stravinsky biographical information.
    - Souvtchinsky, Pierre (1 from F. Lesure)/Morton., 1960-1963 (28), 1967-1982 (32). (Box 69)
      1960-63 includes 12 from L.M., Lesure from 1972 re Souvtchinsky's 80th birthday.
    - Strawinski, F.T. (Box 69)
      3 letters to Charleston, South Carolina. 2 letters from Mary S. Prior and Josephine S. Hughes regarding 19th century musician F.T. Strawinski buried in Charleston.
    - Forbes, Edward/Morton., 1961.; 5 items, 7 pieces. (Box 84)
      re Stravinsky's stay in Boston, 1939-1940.
    - Abravanel, M./Morton., 1961.; 3 items, 5 pieces. (Box 84)
      re Scenes de ballet.
    - A: Morton/ASCAP, Andriessen, Atlantic Monthly, AMP and Ed Allen., 1963-1986.; 10 items, 14 pieces. (Box 84)
      re Stravinsky award and Stravinsky book.
    - Ansermet/Morton., 1960-1961.; 18 items, 24 pieces. (Box 84)
      re Stravinsky book. Topics include Ansermet's transcription of the Prelude to Part II of 'LeSacre du Printemps et al.
    - Morton/ David Noon., 1969.; 1 item 2 pieces. (Box 84)
      re Four Norwegian moods.
    - Fasquelle Editeurs/Morton., 1960-1961.; 13 items, 17 pieces. (Box 84)
      re Stravinsky encyclopedia article.
    - B: Morton/Babitz, Berman, Bessel, Biennale di Venizia, Blazhkov, Boucourechliev, Boulanager, Broude Brothers., 1959-1982.; 30 items, 42 pieces. (Box 84)
      re editions of Stravinsky. Berman comments on his relationship with the Stravinskys (December 28,1961).
    - Boosey & Hawkes/Morton., 1958-1983.; 37 items, 41 pieces. (Box 84)
      re editions of Stravinsky's compositions.
    - C: Morton/CBC, CBS, Clifford Caesar, Jae Carmichael, Cocteau (1960), Conservatoire de Musique de Geneve, Ruth Cowen, Constance Crow., 1960-1985.; 19 items and 29 pieces. (Box 84)
      One item is a clipping from Show Magazine re Cocteau.
    - G: Morton/Eric Ganley, Martin Garbus, Burt Goldstein, Stanley Sadie., 1959-1982.; 13 items, 15 pieces. (Box 84)
      Ganley re books, Garbus re Stravinsky--Craft litigation and Stravinsky papers, Sadie re Stravinsky article in Grove's Dictionary.
    - Craft/Morton., 1983-1987.; 35 items, 67 pieces. (Box 84)
      Includes 6 clippings and a program.
    - D: Morton/Dance Collection--New York Public Library, Edwin Denby, Vincent Duckles, Samuel Dushkin, Alexander Duvois., 1960-1961.; 10 items, 14 pieces. (Box 84)
      re Stravinsky book.
    - Guggenheim: A letter to Igor Stravinsky from the John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation., 1962.; 1 item, 1 piece. (Box 84)
      Applications answered by L.M. 12 December 62. Stravinsky apparently had L.M. respond to this request for references.
    - Godowsky--Morros: From the Paramount Pictures Music Library--Correspondence between Dagmar Godowsky, Richard Copley and Boris Morros--Unsigned contract., 1937, 1975.; 13 items, 15 pieces. (Box 84)
      Photocopies of 1937 documents, except for typed note (dated 7 April 75) from A Friend, the source of the papers.
    - E: Morton/Enciclopedia dello spettacolo, Robert Erickson., 1961-1963.; 5 items, 8 pieces. (Box 84)
      re article on Stravinsky & Le Sacre du Printemps.
    - F: Morton/Faber & Faber & The Bulletin., 1960 & 1964.; 4 items, 9 pieces. (Box 84)
      re page proofs of Memories & commentaries and Monday Evening Concert premiere of Elegy for J.F.K.
    - Footnotes to Stravinsky: Morton/Tempo, Halsey Stevens (1), Eric Walter White (1)., 1978-1979.; 13 items, 28 pieces. (Box 84)
      re L.M., Footnotes to Stravinsky studies. Includes manuscripts of musical examples.
    - K: Morton/Simon Karlinsky, Joseph Kerman, Arthur Knodel, John Kobler, Irving Kolodin., 1960-1983.; 10 items, 12 pieces. (Box 85)
      Karlinsky re article in Box 84. Kerman re Oedipus Rex. Knodel re Rolland translation in Box 69. Kolodin re Morton Footnotes in Box 84.
    - M: Robert Craft/William H. Rosar., 1984-1985.; 7 items, 8 pieces. (Box 85)
      re Stravinsky and motion picture scores.
    - P: Morton/Princeton University Press., 1962.; 2 items, 2 pieces. (Box 85)
      Inquiry re Stravinsky book.
    - Oxford University Press/Morton (predominantly Sheldon Meyer). From Oxford (76). From Morton (31)., 1958-1979.; 107 items, 110 pieces. (Box 85)
      re abandoned book on Stravinsky.
    - O: Morton/The Opera Box, The Open University., 1959, n.d.; 2 items, 2 pieces. (Box 85)
      Opera Box re rare souvenir programs. Open University re Stravinsky by Roger Nichols.
    - New York Philharmonic/Morton (2). To Olivier Voisin (1)., 1976, n.d.; 3 items, 3 pieces. (Box 85)
      Philharmonic request for autograph photograph of Stravinsky. Voisin re copy of Schoenberg letter.
    - Neighbor, Tim/Morton. From Neighbor (25). From Morton: (3)., 1960-1971.; 29 items, 31 pieces. (Box 85)
      re mutual passion for rare books and contemporary music.
    - M: Morton/MacGibbon & Kee, January Maegaard, Oleg Maslenikov, Nathan Broder (Musical Quarterly), Edward P. Morgan, Charles W. Millard., 1957-58, 1961, 1964, 1985.; 14 items, 20 pieces. (Box 85)
      Macgibbon re Stravinsky book. Maegaard re Nutida translation. Maslenikov re Balmont & Gorodetsky. Broder re Norton reprint of Baiser article. Morgan re Stravinsky broadcast. Millard re Picasso.
    - Morton/National Institute of Arts and Letters, E.W. White to D. Mitchell, J. Sample to R.Hill, I. Lowens to Morton. (Box 85)
      White re progress on Stravinsky book (In L.M.'s hand: given to me by R.C.), Hill re StravinskyStar Spangled Banner, National Institute re Stravinsky honors, Lowens re Septet premiere.